

Contact

Phone

+92 324 3329192

Email

mshahzaib101ed@gmail.com

Address

Dubai, UAE

Portfolio

https://iamshahzaib.com/
https://github.com/mshahzaib101
https://www.linkedin.com/in/mshahzaib101

Skills

- Javascript
- React is
- Node js
- Next.js/Gatsby.js
- SQL/noSQL
- Firebase
- Express.js
- AWS
- Fastify.js
- React Native
- MongoDB
- Python
- Mailchimp/Hubspot
- Graphql
- GCP
- Docker
- Tensorflow

Muhammad Shahzaib

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

I am Shahzaib, Full-stack developer from UAE / Pakistan with a focus on React.js Development for the last 4+ years. I have specialized in responsive web and application development for startups and small to large size businesses. My skill set includes wide-ranging expertise in Javascript frameworks such as React.js, Next.js and Gatsby.js. I am also great at Node.js, Bootstrap, Firebase, AWS, MongoDB, Python and a whole host of other technologies, and libraries. Whatever your needs are, I will find a solution that fits it.

Experience

2020 - Present

Vaionex I Delaware, USA

Senior Full-stack developer

I am working as a Full-stack and Lead developer at Vaionex since last 2 years. Vaionex provides blockchain solutions. I have worked and led some great projects, here are some of them:

- Satolearn: It is a Blockchain learning platform.
- Musicart: It is a music NFTs trading platform built on BSV.
- Metashard: It is a database solution for bitcoin transactions.
- ApiAndMe: It helps to connect APIs to the world with bitcoin micropayments.
- Dojo Discover: It is a platform where investors can invest in Web 3.0 startups.

2019 - 2020

Upwork I US

Full-stack developer

I was Top Rated freelancer on Upwork in 2020. I worked with 20+ clients mostly working on Next.js and express.js. You can check out reviews from my profile.

- <u>Upwork</u>
- Fiverr

some of the great projects on which I worked as freelancer:

- Yeschef: It provide online cooking classes and connects people with chefs.
- <u>Chemishield</u>: Waste management solution

2019 - 2019

Hasati I California, US

MERN-stack developer

I was working as a MERN developer in Hasati, mostly working on React.js and Node.js, building admin panels that handle realtime telecom data.

- Designed and developed user-friendly admin panels on React.js, including an optimized check-out page that increased user clicks, and subsequently customer purchases by 20%
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Developed dynamic and interactive websites that ensured high traffic, page views, and User Experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales revenue

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Urdu

Expertise

- Full Stack Development
- Project Management
- Project Lead
- Database Management
- Testing & Debugging

2018 - 2019 Axiom I Pakistan

Front-end developer

I was working as a front-end developer in Axiom. I was mostly working on React.js, building responsive PWAs for the clients.

Education

2018 - 2020

Cambridge A'levels UK GCSE

University of Cambridge

2018

Cambridge O'levels UK GCSE

University of Cambridge